[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome to us the Oscar Beach Show
episode 140. I hope you're all doing
very well and before we begin let me
wish you all a very happy Diwali as we
know Diwali is tomorrow and I suspect
that some of you must have celebrated
Diwali a little early after watching the
cricket match today right
so yeah so I wish you all have very
happy Diwali and I too watch the cricket
match today for a change uh these days I
don't watch cricket but today I thought
let me watch it and it was uh certainly
well worth the time
so um let's see who all is there with us
I can see Harry Potter arsh the Dragon
Emperor Vivan Shivan shashwat amritansu
Joseph Stalin
swapna
samarth priyanshi Mazar nil saket
abhinav
Ducks sharks Aryan shubham the oxboss
Ashish bhumi shravani Vladimir
adityanath vaibhav Mishra Abhishek
sarkar sriram
Akash nikunj Alpha Devendra Divine Akash
Prasad
pankaj the guy shubham anahita Punit
accepted and lots of other people good
evening good day to all of you thank you
for being on the show with us all
tonight so um
let's take a few questions
so uh
yesterday I did the uh I I kind of
rebooted the Indian interest podcast and
I spoke about a variety of geopolitical
issues that are of importance right I
spoke about that so some of those topics
may be repeated today because lots of
people have asked again lots of
questions about similar questions about
the same topics so some of the questions
will be kind of repeated but yeah I'm
always happy to ask you to answer your
questions even if they're repeated
because many of these things are very
important and things are changing uh
geopolitically very rapidly right events
are going at a very rapid pace so we
will discuss various issues today
including geopolitics including history
Etc so let's take what is question
number one where is question number one
okay yes yes this is by chiching and
rajat do share your tips when you come
live again and how much anti-india
activity did you witness in Lac would
like would love to know your experience
there so yes as you all know I was uh no
I did not do any live streams last week
because I was traveling uh usually I am
on doing some podcasts or doing some
collaboration somewhere but this time I
was uh traveling on my own so um
a few months ago if you recall I did
this I had this conversation with Dr
Edward lutwak uh who was one of the
world's foremost jio strategists right
and the conversation was mainly centered
around China and the threat that it
represents to India and what it means to
the rest of the world right so we were
discussing mainly China and National
Security from India's perspective in
that podcast and in during the
conversation he asked me whether I had
been to arunachal Pradesh and I said I
have not been there and then he went on
to describe the geography and the
terrain of Arun and the difficulties for
the Indian Armed Forces to reach the
Border areas and those things and I was
thinking to myself wow this guy is not
even Indian but he knows my territories
border regions better than me so then I
thought that I should actually myself go
and you know visit some of the Border
areas and do some fact finding of my own
and familiarize myself with the Border
conditions of our nation so that's what
I did the the past week I spent a week
or so in Northern India mainly in the
ladakhir intention tree right and yeah
so it was a very interesting experience
uh I did visit the loc between India and
the temporary nation state of Pakistan
temporarily yeah I did also want to go
to the Lac with in between India and
Tibet where which is currently
temporarily occupied by China because of
weather Etc I was not able to actually
make it to the lse but I was in in the
region right
so um one of the things the first thing
I had in mind you know was that I will
not take any photographs of any military
installations India has a lot of
military presence obviously naturally in
this region and I was very conscious I
made a very conscious decision that I
will not take any pictures or any film
any video and whatever of any military
activity not activity but military
installations or or outposts such or
whatever it is you know in the region
and I did not do that I did take
photographs I mean thousands of
photographs of of the terrain of the of
the region and all that and some of
those photographs did actually
accidentally capture some military
activity not in the military outposts
but on the roads and I will not release
those pictures anytime soon maybe not
for the next two three years for sure
but my experience was very interesting
so let me share some pictures you know
because a picture tells you a thousand
words a picture is equivalent to a
thousand words so as you can see this is
in ladakh and it's already snowing there
winter seems to have come rather early
so that's me and that's the the snowy
region in the background right very
snowy there
and as you can see it's a very beautiful
landscape I would uh would like it would
be great if people would visit it more
you know instead of going abroad
Indians want to go abroad and see
mountains and snow and things like that
well we have incredible natural beauty
within India itself so it would be great
if Indians would visit our own regions
instead of going abroad and contribute
to the local economy so this is just one
one example right it's incredible
natural beauty
is very close by so you can see this is
not exactly a military installation but
it's just uh or some kind of Memorial
right so it's about the sea urchin
Warrior sea urchin is very close by to
this to the place where you which you
see in the picture here and this is very
close to the LFC where the enemy can
actually observe you the pakistanis
which who temporarily occupy some places
or some some territory nearby so this is
a photograph you must have seen already
in the thumbnail
and this is me striking a very silly
pose and behind me you can actually see
Pakistan occupied Kashmir it is actually
Pakistan occupied gilgit baltistan
behind me right and this is uh the
village of Tang which is considered
which is called the last border Village
of India
and uh this is yeah from a different
angle all of what you see in the
background the mountains the valley Etc
the the past between two mountain ranges
all that that is all temporarily
Pakistan occupied that's what it is
right and uh the mountain peaks behind
me in this picture are currently
occupied temporarily by by Pakistan so
the mountain peaks behind me are pokojk
or Pakistan
so I was over there and they actually
have bunkers and and um and uh
encampments up there in those mountain
tops they are watching us but we they
are not visible from from here and I
also I like I said I took thousands of
pictures and some later when I checked
the pictures I found certain things
which are rather hard to explain for
example this for example that right some
very strange pictures that I can't quite
which are a little hard to explain this
is the pangong so region there's a
beautiful Lake over there
so this picture was taken in that region
and it is slightly yeah as you can see
so uh yeah
so that was the experience I did not
witness any anti-india activity as such
apart from the fact that the pakistanis
Occupy certain territories in that
region west of where I was
that obviously is Untamed activity that
is a temporary phase of Forestry in a
decade or so it will no longer be the
case and the Indian flag will be visible
everywhere
so that is in brief about my trip uh
that fact-finding trip that I did to the
northern border regions of India uh I
did not take much video because when you
are doing filming you don't really
experience the place right I wanted to
actually experience the place and
understand what the terrain is like and
what the Border regions are like
if you want to do a vlog for instance
you need a crew with you it's very hard
to do a vlog yourself and then
experience the place and understand the
place so I did not take any film very
little video I just took lots of
photographs as you and some of them I
showed you and that was the experience I
could not make my way all the way to
razangla for instance which is uh along
the lse close to the lse between India
and Tibet uh currently uh temporarily
Chinese occupied Tibet in the future I
would like to do that in the future I
would also like to go and visit
arunachal and other places as well so
yeah this was uh
a brief interview for me a small
fact-finding trip for me and it was a
very interesting incredible natural
beauty I mean you should all go and
experience it yourself incredible
natural beauty and I actually went there
at not the not a good time to go there
from from a weather perspective because
I went there in Autumn right in the in
the
second and third week of October when
winter is almost there it's extremely
cold in the city of Lei it's already in
the night time in in early morning it's
the temperature goes down to minus two
minus three or minus four perhaps and in
if you go further north the temperature
goes on minus seven already maybe maybe
close to -10 now right so uh it's not a
good time for tourists to go there the
altitude is incredibly High the city of
lay which is which is in the in the
valley region in in ladakh is at an
altitude of 3.5
000 kilometers or meters above sea level
that's almost 13 000 or so feet above
sea level which is incredibly high it's
very hard to breathe there for a person
who lives at sea level typically right
so the the altitude is very high the
oxygen levels are low although it takes
time to acclimatize over there and if
you go further uh you know if you if you
go to higher altitudes like in the
pangong region it gets even harder and
the temperature it gets even colder so
it's not for everybody typically you
would want to go with there in April May
June July maybe around August I went in
Autumn almost winter so it was but I
enjoy the cold
and I was told to use sunscreen yeah
because the the sunlight there is very
direct it's very harsh but I thought
like sunscreen is it's a cosmetic I
don't need that and as a result I've got
this badly sunburned and wind burned
face as you can see these patches of
dark yeah I I kind of get sunburned very
easily that's what I've discovered but
anyway so that's the kind of uh
experience that I had that's the trip
that I did to understand the Border
Region's first hand what the climate
what the terrain is like what the
geography is like what challenges our
great armed forces in our brave soldiers
face there all that I got a very good
understanding of that first hand
understanding and I would like to repeat
that in other parts of the Border
regions of India as well in the future
so that's the kind of experience that I
had
um and maybe in the future I may even do
a vlog if I can I would need to hire a
you know so a crew for that I I will do
that in the future
right now let's go on to the other
questions
okay this is by birkaran Singh nil
badori and Avinash
what about you
what about U.S national security policy
saying India is their major strategic
partner Neil says did this video come up
after U.S declared its national security
policy stating India as an ally I think
not
and Avinash says then what about
mentioning India's name so many times in
the recently released national security
policy calling India an ally and so on
so forth even though we only call
America a partner is it just a bluff or
a tactic or a signal for change so I I
have said various things about the US
from India's perspective and lots of
people are now saying that I was
completely wrong because the Americans
have called India and Ally International
security policy document and I discussed
this yesterday as well but let's discuss
it all over again because I'm sure many
people may not have seen what I said
yesterday or heard listen to what I said
yesterday so
the Americans did release their national
security policy document and
in that document they have they have
mentioned India as a as a major defense
partner and and uh and then as as an
ally right
Now understand this all Warfare all all
diplomacy all geopolitics all
geostrategy is based on Deception it's
based on not letting your enemies and
your partners and your allies know what
you're up to and what your long-term
plans and objectives and strategies and
tactics are you should never let anyone
else know what you're thinking and what
you're planning so if a nation like the
US releases an official national
security policy not the argument you
cannot take it seriously it is only for
public consumption it's for fooling
people who are very gullible like like
the like many of the comments that one
sees right and I'm sure lots of other
so-called
geopolitics observers and commentators
must have been very enthused about the
fact that America is called India and
Ally and mentioned India seven or eight
times in the document I I see first of
all please understand I don't watch any
other geopolitics videos I don't follow
such channels and such writers and all
that so I have no idea who said what but
I get the feeling I get the sense that
many of the other
geopolitical uh experts seem to be very
happy about this so I am not happy about
this I'm not it doesn't excite me at all
because
any document that is released in public
is only for public consumption it does
not reflect what that Nation actually
seeks and intends to do
it's all about deception
so if they have mentioned India seven
eight times or whatever why are you all
getting so happy about it if they have
called India and Ally so what it's words
if you I mean have I have you not
listened to me enough
how many times have I said this over and
over again words don't matter only
actions matter
and yet you all get happy about this oh
my goodness
India is now uh the Americans have
called us an ally they mentioned us
seven or eight times in the document
great success Nacho
I mean what is this
what is this why why are people so happy
about this look at the actions the
Americans are doing
they have brought Pakistan out of the
fatf gray list so now Any Nation can
invest in Pakistan without worrying
about uh any sanctions on the U.S from
from a terrorism perspective right so
Pakistan has now been given a clean
the Americans are giving Pakistan a half
billion dollar upgrade to their F-16
fighter jet Fleet
these are actions not words
the American visa States like South
Korea and Japan are now investing big
time in Pakistan these are actions not
words words don't matter there are so
many other things the American
ambassador
there is no American ambassador in India
right but there's an American ambassador
in in Pakistan who
recently visited the illegally and
temporarily occupied
part of Kashmir which is which is
temporarily occupied by Pakistan and
they called it he or she whoever it is
called it ajk whatever the hell that
means right instead of pojk right so
they are all they are supporting
Pakistan in all these matters these are
actions when a diplomat issues a
statement on Twitter and and uses a
certain term that's an action it's not a
it's not what it's worth anymore it's a
it's it's a signal of support
so when you see all these things when
you see the actions they are all
anti-india when they are
aiding and and uh
arming Pakistan that's an anti-india
action that's a hostile act against
India these wonderful words don't matter
but Indians are so emotional and so
gullible
yeah that yeah they said this so now
everything is fine
how silicon people can can people be
have you learned nothing from me
I just don't get it I just don't get it
why people are so so gullible in India
so that's what I have to say about this
I can see lots of people these are just
three of the comments I'm not saying
they're all like all harsh or whatever
but I'll I'm just I have seen lots of
comments in that you you know you're all
wrong see what the Americans have said
now see what they've stated they've
called India a major defense partner and
and the Strategic Ally and they've
mentioned India seven or eight times in
the national security policy so yeah
Abhijit you are wrong and Americans
actually are pro-india how silly how
gullible is that I just don't understand
how people can be socially anyhow that's
what we are I think it's going to be a
long time before we Indians grow up
so please please glow up grow up at
least those of you who are watching yeah
all right next samarth and rajat so much
says with the resignation of release
Trust
would rishis should not be able to take
England out of its misery or will we
witness another Sri Lanka for the UK and
samarth says will another clown Boris
Johnson come back as the new PM now that
Liz truss has resigned so my my question
first of all is why do we think that is
a person who's capable of taking in
England out of its misery
why what do we know about richest he's
an Indian origin guy and people are so
so happy about that my God Rishi sunak
has a second chance now he may become
the PM who cares who is he he's another
nobody
I had said a few weeks ago that Liz
trust is a nobody and she will achieve
nothing and people were really angry
about that I saw lots of very
um Angry comments saying that who the
hell do you think you are who you are
who who are you who are you to say that
Liz trust will do nothing and who
whatever well I have turned out to be
absolutely correct my my words have been
have I mean you know she's already gone
one of the shortest serving Prime
Ministers of all time in the UK if not
the shortest serving prime minister
she's a nobody similarly in my opinion
Sonic is going to achieve nothing if
even if it does become the PM of the UK
of England and we don't even know if you
will be able to do that so even if it
does become the PM of the UK it will not
make any difference to us or to the UK
the UK is the New Japan
apart from Shinzo abedin you've had a
long procession of nobodies who became
PM of Japan for a certain period of time
they achieved nothing and they
disappeared and nobody remembers them
the only person who mattered version and
we know what happened to him he was one
guy who actually mattered he was one guy
one Japanese leader who was actually a
genuine friend of India and I always
said that there are no friends in
geopolitics but but Shinzo was a genuine
friend of India and we know what
happened to him so now the same thing
has happened to the UK if you look at
the the record the record of the past
few years the past let's say couple of
Decades of the PMS of UK they are all
nobodies you had Gordon Brown you had
Theresa May you had Boris Johnson you
had a few other people who I don't
recall and latest the latest person was
list trust they came and went they come
and go and nothing ever happens the UK
is see really what's really happening is
that the UK is now being administered
from from Washington
the UK is a versatile State it's a
colony it's an outpost of the U.S it
doesn't matter who's the PM of the UK
that person has no power whatsoever
whatsoever and no decision-making
ability whatsoever if some people are
gonna be upset about that well cope
because that is the truth and I'm and
mark my words whoever is the next PM of
the UK is going to be another nobody and
that person is going to achieve once
again nothing of any significance so
whether it's rishis whether it's Boris
Johnson whether it is what's her name
swella whatever the hell she is these
people are nobodies they have no
leadership ability whatsoever their only
ambition is to put pm on their CV
take Boris Johnson for instance he's in
his entire ambition was to become PM a
genuine leader has bigger Ambitions a
genuine leader wants to take the country
forward and becoming PM is a step in
that direction it is not the end goal
the end goal is to take the nation
forward and make the nation greater
and to do that they have to become PM
that's why they want to become the PM
not to you know to to gain the glory and
the prestige that comes with the PM
position but to use the PM position as a
means of taking the nation forward and
serving the nation that's what real
leadership is like these people like
Boris Johnson Etc and whoever else the
swillar Or List trust they only want to
become BM because it adds a feather to
their cap and it looks great on anyone's
CV
these people are nobodies there is no
leadership quality or ability there
right they only seek to serve the real
master the real master sits the real
Masters sit in Washington in the
Pentagon that's all it is so it doesn't
matter who becomes the PM
it doesn't matter at all Nothing's Gonna
Change I don't see the UK becoming
another Sri Lanka right
the UK the UK is still very valuable
it's still very useful to the US why
would they ruin it they will ensure that
there is no genuine leader who can
emerge that's what the Americans will
ensure that no genuine leader can ensure
can emerge in the UK who would actually
care for the national interest of the UK
and its people
today the UK's foreign policy is an
extension of the American foreign policy
everything the UK does serves the United
States it is made to look like there is
democracy and blah blah blah but it all
seeks to serve the long-term strategic
interests and the national interests in
the
you know monetary and financial
interests of the US that's all it is the
UK is nothing but a colony a LaSalle
State at best so they will not turn it
into another Sri Lanka they will not
ruin it they will use it as long as they
can and as long as it's useful and it's
still quite useful so that's what's
going to happen but whoever becomes PM
next is going to be an insignificant
person whether it is I don't know why
Indians are so happy about who cares who
is he he's not serving the he's not
serving India in any way whatsoever even
if it does become the PM he's gonna have
no actual power so these people are
insignificant and we should stop wasting
our time over these people
froster says I think the New Britain PM
will be in Indian because Americans will
try try to give India more reasons to be
on the side of the West without giving
us any real benefits this person froster
is intelligent he or she gets it
yeah he I mean the Americans know very
well that Indians are extremely
emotional Indians like prestige
Indians like status
even if the status comes at the at the
expense of India's nationalities doesn't
matter
Indians don't even understand what is
the meaning of the national interest
yeah so yeah this is a very interesting
thought that froster has put forth that
maybe the Americans will make uh maybe
Rishi sunak or maybe what's her name
swella the next PM of the UK so it will
it will so then there will be a lot of
pressure from the Indian voting
population for the Indian government to
become more progressed because see now
we've got a Indian origin UK PM but we
will India will gain no real benefits
from it everyone knows that I mean not
everyone knows that but you should know
that that it doesn't benefit India in
any way whatsoever whoever is the PM of
the UK
think about it there are so many Indian
origin CEOs in the west whereas Google
whether it's uh what's it called
Facebook or there are dozens of
companies right big corporations The
Fortune 500 corporations lots of these
CEOs are Indians what in what way does
it benefit India in no way whatsoever
and yet Indians dance and rejoice
whenever one of these people are sends
to the top post these people merely
serve an unseen unknown and larger
master
so that's how it is that's how the real
world works and this is what none of
your geopolitical experts will tell you
but that's what it is so I'm glad that
froster has learned something at least
from watching me
and I'm really glad to see that so yeah
maybe maybe Foster is right maybe the
Americans will will install an Indian
origin UK PM yeah to make the gullible
Indian population populists rejoice and
dance and then pressurize the Indian
government to become more pro pro West
because see the West is pro-india
apparently no it's not
right next question
Trojan Horse says what do you think XI
jinping's third term is going to be like
do you think he will be even more
aggressive I think it's quite likely
that Xi Jinping will be more aggressive
and more more assertive uh the 20th
National Congress of the CCP has just
concluded
it ended you know on a very
on a very ominous note with the public
humiliation of
I think a decade in China
and uh
and it is under 100's leadership that
China experienced year after year of of
uh double-digit growth of its GDP and
then in 2012 Mr took over the Reigns
from Mr hujinta and now 10 years later
he has publicly humiliated Mr hujintao
by having him by by creating the
spectacle of Mr hujinta being physically
lifted out of his seat by two bodyguards
or security people and and pulled out of
the proceedings of the uh of the 20th
National Congress of the CCP Mr hujinta
was later allowed to come back and vote
or whatever but that spectacle that was
done is something that people will
remember forever
so yeah
so Mr Mr Xi Jinping Mr she has uh
consolidated his power in the Chinese
Communist Party in the CCP in China he
has created uh he has packed the power
power echelons with hand-picked
candidates right uh and yeah so his his
hold over the CCP is more or less
absolute right now and yet China is
going through a very bad time now the
economy is not doing well they are not
even releasing the GDP figures anymore
because that's how bad the economy is
doing the built-in Road initiative is
dead in the water it's frozen it's not
going anywhere for anywhere anywhere
ahead yeah there are lockdowns lots of
lockdowns in China again and again
because now it looks like China is the
only nation that's suffering from the
coronavirus pandemic the rest of the
world is is kind of looks like it's it's
it's gone beyond that but the Chinese
are imposing lockdowns so repeatedly in
various places like Shanghai and so on
one wonders why that that is the case
but that's what's happening right the
Chinese are struggling even now with the
covet so China is not doing well China
doesn't look like it's going to become a
superpower in time soon because the Bri
is dead in the water it's not working
anymore and they have their great hope
of for Russia coming to beg to them as a
consequence of the Ukraine war there
also has not happened because India has
helped us out by buying 50 times more
oil than it was buying from Russia
earlier
despite American threats and warnings
so Russia has been saved by India Russia
has not been forced to go and beg to
China and become a Chinese massage state
so the Chinese
their superpower Ambitions are well kind
of uh they're not happening it's not
happening anymore it's not going to
happen anytime soon
so there could be problems in the days
in months and years ahead for Mr Xi
Jinping you know uh
a Chinese leader has to perform they
have to
show results that's how the entire
system works it's a ruthless system it's
a brutal system
any Chinese leader who shows weakness uh
that person doesn't last it simply
doesn't work even if that person has
taken complete her control of the CCP or
whatever if you don't perform in China
as a leader you're dead you're finished
so Mr Xi Jinping could get desperate if
things go things keep on going bad right
if the economy doesn't emerge out of its
its downturn I mean things are going to
get worse there's a food crisis there's
an energy crisis in the world
um
which has been created but created by
the Americans there are these sanctions
the Americans have imposed on China the
export controls for semiconductors and
all that so so the Chinese semiconductor
industry seems to be
finished right now yeah
it's it's almost like a nuclear attack
on the Chinese semiconductor and Chip
industry so now the Chinese even if they
try to control capture Taiwan if the the
Taiwan is destroy those those shipping
factors and then the Chinese will be
left with nothing so it becomes even
more difficult for them to to try and
you know invade Taiwan or conquer Taiwan
Chinese are in a very difficult position
and
that's something that could make Xi
Jinping desperate and make him
aggressive and you know
lead to various uh
one could say ill advisable actions on
behalf of China on the on the part of
China maybe if there is a perception
among the Chinese population that the
president is not doing well then the
president May out of desperation do a
gamble you know gamble the
a short war with some Nation whom they
could try to humiliate and that would
bring back The Prestige of the President
right
so yeah things like that could happen
it's it's it's a we are living through
dangerous times right now these are very
dangerous times there are there are
potential trouble spots all across the
world mainly in Asia also in Europe you
have the Russia Ukraine conflict that's
that's simmering right now what's going
on Russia is waiting for winter because
winter will teach the Europeans a big
lesson right the Russians know that it's
gonna happen it's coming there are hard
times are here for for Europe winter is
coming and over here in Asia there are
all these these these troubled spots you
know places where Anything Could Happen
anytime depending on the leadership
there is the entire undemarkated border
between Tibet and India Tibet is
currently temporarily occupied by China
right now China has the upper hand it's
way more powerful than India for now yes
from a conventional perspective from a
military perspective from an economic
perspective and so on but India also is
more than capable of Defending itself
when it comes to child to China so there
is the entire undemarkated border
between India and Tibet which is a flash
potential Flashpoint there is obviously
Pakistan the Rogue terrorist nation that
is supported by the Americans and the
Chinese as the counterbalance to India
that again is a huge problem for the
whole world
and then there is Taiwan then there is
the Chinese dispute with the Japanese in
the in the senkaku islands which they
call the aoi islands there are so many
trouble spots in Asia so yes Mr Xi
Jinping if he gets desperate he could
make a move on Taiwan he would he could
make a move against India you could try
and make a move against Japan Taiwan is
very dangerous for him because the
Americans have a very strong presence
there the Americans are still the
dominant power in the world Japan once
again it's supported by the Americans
the Americans have more than 130
military bases permanent military bases
on Japanese territory so it's very
dangerous for the Chinese to try and you
know tangle with Japan the Japanese have
a very very dangerous submarine Fleet as
well the Chinese are really scared of
that when it comes to India there are
certain Redlands the Chinese cannot
cross if they try something that they
could pay a very heavy price for that as
well because yep yeah they have their
conventional military strength could be
better than that of India overall but in
the Tibet region they are very much
exposed
yeah and uh in the mountainous regions
you know things are different it's not
like conventional Warfare Mountain
Warfare is very different you know and
in Mountain Warfare it's often the
amount of training and the quality of
the training that your armed forces have
had and the quality of your personal
that matters because in Mountain Warfare
you need to do hand to hand Warfare
sometimes and it's all about strategies
and tactics and also about the kind of
weapons you have India has excellent
missiles the brahmos missile can perform
Feats of what you could call almost
magic and India obviously has the
Ultimate Weapon that the Chinese don't
want to taste nobody wants that weapon
to ever be used in war again but we have
it and that's the deterrence
so I think that it is possible that XI
jinping's third term could be turbulent
it could be
uh it it could uh
give us it could it could it could uh
possibly be more aggressive from his
perspective and time will tell us but
yes this decade is crucial for India for
China for Asia for the rest of the world
we are witnessing this increasing
bifurcation of the global world order
the West against the East that's what's
happening
and obviously in the East we have all
these problems Russia doesn't trust
China India doesn't trust China and
China doesn't trust anyone
right now we are witnessing some sort of
systemic cooperation between Russia and
China but everybody knows that Russia
the Russians do not trust China and the
Russians have the world's largest
nuclear Arsenal and they have one of the
most powerful military in the world we
have not even seen a fraction of that
being used in Ukraine
the Russians are keeping it for later
because in the future we they may need
it so yeah
we are witnessing a very turbulent
period of world history this decade is
going to be crucial
in in determining the way the rest of
the 21st century is going to go and
right now anything could happen we don't
know who's going to come out on top the
Americans are still the dominant
superpower they are the only superpower
in the world
the Russians are the major Asian power
and the two other great powers are India
and Russia France is kind of a medium
power
and there are no other real powers in
the world Japan is a U.S result state so
it's not an independent nation neither
is South Korea neither is Germany
neither is the UK
France has a semi-independent foreign
policy and Israel well
well Israel also one would have to say
despite the the good relations between
India and Israel one the truth is that
Israel also to a large extent uh its
foreign policy is a reflection of the
U.S foreign policy yeah and
Israel is greatly supported by the U.S
even though during times when the
Democrats in power relations between
Israel and the U.S are kind of testy
kind of troublesome kind of strained
that's always been the case in recent
times at least I mean look at the way
look at the kind of relationship the
Israel and the U.S had during the Barack
Obama eight years as president very
tense relationship very hostile
relationship right between especially
between the two leaders Obama and
Netanyahu but overall Israel's foreign
policy is to a large extent or to a
certain extent a reflection or a
continuation of American foreign policy
so Israel obviously is is a nation that
is to has a special place in India's
foreign policy a lot of our interests
align
so one would hope that Israel continues
to prosper and do well and remains
reasonably independent from the U.S
and yeah that's how it is so this is a
very crucial decade and it's a I think
it's going to be a very turbulent decade
I hope there is no war but anything's
possible anything is indeed possible
babish says could we see a democratic
government in China in the future
I do not see democracy ever taking place
taking a foothold in China unless unless
there is a complete regime change
orchestrated by the West which seems
extremely unlikely right now see
democracy has never been a Chinese thing
the Chinese have never been a democratic
culture they have never had democracy
they've always had an imperial system of
government from the very beginning so if
you look back at Chinese history
China is about three thousand three and
a half thousand years old if you are if
you are if you want to be charitable to
them
three three and a half thousand years
old that's how old the civilization is
and obviously if you look at the
archaeological record it goes back in
time but the actual culture civilization
starts around three and a half or so
thousand years before today and it's
always had an imperial system it's never
been Democratic on the other hand India
always had the mahajanapada and the
janapada system which is a form of
democracy it's an Indian form of
democracy in which you had elected Kings
who could be deposed when they did not
perform well so the people were
Paramount these were Republics
that's what you had in India the
janapadas and the great
the Chinese have always had an imperial
system always so democracy is not
something that's in that's integral or
inherent through Chinese culture it's
it's an unchinese concept right
uh so which is why I do not see
democracy the there's there is this uh
there is this band rock band called Guns
and Roses if some of you have heard of
it when I was a kid it was a very big
deal one of the biggest bands in the
world at that time when I was a kid and
they went on this long Hiatus they broke
up and all that then there was this
album they were making for a very long
time it was eventually released I don't
know how many years ago and that our
that album was called Chinese Democracy
so that's a myth it's a mirage it's not
going to happen yeah and since it is
something that's not a part of the
culture why would we even want the
Chinese to become a democratic Nation or
culture let them be what they want why
should we force something that is not
that is foreign to them upon them
if you want the Chinese to become
Democratic it's like force-fitting a
foreign alien concept on a culture where
it doesn't belong I am perfectly happy
with the Chinese having their own system
of governance whatever it is if it's an
imperial system like you like you have
today that well and good it's up to them
it is an internal matter of China
in in international relations we have to
respect other nations and other cultures
internal matters don't interfere in that
that's the that's the foundational
principle actually of the International
System which obviously the most powerful
Nations keep breaking all the time
but it's about mutual respect it's about
it's about uh non-interference in the
internal matters for the Nations so I
would say I I do not see this ever
happening unless there is a complete
coup and the Chinese system is broken
down by the west and the West is able to
affect a complete regime change which is
extremely unlikely even if they're able
to impose a demo a so-called democratic
government in China it won't last long
because it's not something that is part
of Chinese culture so to make it short
to answer in one sentence I do not ever
see a democratic government in China in
the future
and that's fine
okay yashwan says what are the
implications of Pakistan being removed
out of the fatf gray list why is the U.S
pursuing short-term interests doesn't it
realize it's doing the same mistake it
did in the 90s again how should India
tackle this growing adversarial Nexus
between the US and Pakistan
uh why do we see this as a mistake from
the from the U.S perspective from the
U.S perspective let's let's think let's
put ourselves in the shoes of the U.S
right now for for a minute
so the Americans are currently the only
superpower in the world what what is the
definition of a superpower the
definition from my perspective of a
superpower is a nation or a power
that can intervene militarily at any par
in any part of the world at 60 minutes
notice within 60 Minutes they can
intervene militarily that's a superpower
so by from that definition there's only
one superpower which is the us they can
intervene anywhere military anywhere in
the world at 60 minutes notice more or
less right the Chinese can't do that the
Russians can't do it and India can't do
it right now yeah so the US is the only
superpower now if you are a superpower
you want that superpower status to go on
forever you don't want that to erode
away and so you may have you may pursue
certain short-term interests or certain
long-term interest based on what your
long-term objectives are so from the U.S
perspective they don't want
new competitors or new threats to emerge
on the horizon on the long-term Horizon
that could Nations that would become a
threat in the next 10 20 30 years India
very much fits the bill of a long-term
competitor to the U.S India's economy is
growing India's population is Young
energetic very bright very capable huge
potential India has everything India in
the next 20 years could become the next
China India is very much capable of
doing that and the Americans as a
superpower you don't think short term
you think long term you think on a
50-year horizon and 100 Year Horizon and
based on those calculations you do
short-term Things based as long as it is
the the your short-term actions serve
your long-term interests
so if you are the US you want
to ensure that India doesn't rise too
much and Rise too fast and so to do that
you counter balance India with another
Power when Pakistan is tailor-made for
that
the British created Pakistan for this
for this very specific purpose to
counterbalance India and to keep
bleeding India and hitting India right
that's that's the the only purpose for
which Pakistan was created
and it was to to serve the British
geopolitical interests in the region and
it now serves the American and Chinese
to some extent geopolitical interests in
the Indian subcontinental region and in
Asia overall so that's why the Americans
are playing these games they have
reopened the Cold War Playbook they
always accused India of having a cold
war mentality well now they're quite
about that because they are doing the
same thing
they actually have a cold war mentality
we are now in Cold War 2.0
the Americans have uh essentially tamed
the dragon to a large extent kovid was a
disaster for China
you know
I mean I personally myself have been
guilty of calling this the Wuhan virus
but now I'm wondering whether it was
really a buhan virus that's all I'll say
about this so kovit was a complete
disaster for China it derailed their bid
for superpower status
look at who it benefited it certainly
did not benefit China it was a complete
disaster for China and it was great for
the U.S
so that's what Kobe did so
so now that the now that China is more
or less under control they would like to
control India and that's why they are
now
supporting Pakistan in a variety of ways
and so that's why they have removed I
mean it's the fat of the financial
action task force that has rebooted
Pakistan out of the gray list but all
these institutions are controlled by the
largest power in the world more or less
which is the US so now Pakistan can
receive funding and investments from
various Nations without those Nations
having to worry about the possibility of
their Investments being used for
terrorist activities and any we all know
that they will anyway be used for
terrorist activities because the only
purpose of Pakistan's existence is as
that of a terrorist nation which is
anti-india
so the Americans are pursuing their
interests in this manner
they are also uh
via their various basal States also
supporting Pakistan by by Japan via
South Korea and in a variety of other
ways and there's a whole lot that's
going on
so it's not a mistake from the
perspective of the U.S because it did
not Boomerang on them it did not hurt
them much
right they did whatever they did with
the pakistanis in the 1970s 80s and 90s
it served the U.S national interest it
was very bad for India it was very bad
for Pakistani people of course but it
served the US so it's not a mistake from
that perspective from their perspective
so they will do it again whenever
required so what should India do about
this how should India tackle the growing
adversarial Nexus between the U.S and
Pakistan
the first thing India has to understand
the government understands this very
well but the people of Indians need to
understand this India has no allies
India is on its own India is is doing
this very delicate tightrope walk Act
India is balancing various powers in
various forces
and
trying to find its own way in the 21st
century if India goes to war with let's
say Pakistan who's going to help India
nobody
if India goes to war with let's say
China who's going to come and help India
not the Americans and the Russians are
currently not in a position to help
India
so whatever India does India is on its
own that's the first thing the people of
India have to understand
the second thing
in the long term over a 20-year Horizon
the only thing India needs to do I have
said this a thousand times I'm gonna say
it again another another thousand times
the only
correct course of action for India is to
grow its economy India needs to First
reach the 5 trillion dollar GDP Mark and
then the 10 trillion dollar GDP mark
and keep growing
India has the potential to become the
largest economy in the world because
historically that's been India's
historical position in the world the
largest economy by far by a mile that's
what India has always been India has to
regain that position Come What May
and for that India needs at least a
decade of Peace So India has to somehow
or the other ensure that the next 10
years there is no big conflict that
India gets embroiled in no major war no
major conflict keep all the various
forces counterbalanced in some way or
the other and reach anyhow the 10
trillion dollar economy attended
indology GDP mark because as your GDP
grows as your economy grows your
military budget also increases
correspondingly and as your military
budget increases you gain more military
muscle
and as your military muscle becomes
larger Other Nations become more and
more wary of trying to
get enrolled with you in any military
misadventure because it would be fatal
for them right so that's the only course
of action for India there's only one
course of action now that's the
long-term plan that's a long-term
strategy how to reach there it depends
as the world changes we will have to
keep on changing our our actions and our
tactics the tactics will keep changing
the strategy and the goal overall goal
the policies have to be the same but the
tactics and strategies can keep changing
depending on how the winds blow the
geopolitical winds blow so that's what
India needs to do there's only one way
to tackle all these problems it's by
growing it's by growing and regaining
our historical position as the world's
largest economy that's the nothing else
nothing can should come in our way this
this is non-negotiable that's the only
thing India needs to do and it's not
easy it's obviously not easy it's easy
to say about speak about this it's not
easy to do but we have the right
leadership right now in position
God forbid if the leadership changes we
are dead we finished understand that
okay samarth says you pointed out that
India is no longer in the U.S Camp
considering this how do you see India
Japan ties in the future of the Quad
India and the U.S probably have this one
common interest so no impact on India
Japan ties
um India Japan ties are changing
unfortunately I pointed out that India
is no no India was never in the U.S camp
but India and the US were coming closer
together because of the rise of China
now like I just said
the Chinese rise has stopped it has the
the Chinese Juggernaut the Chinese
growth engine has stalled the covet
pandemic has been a complete and utter
disaster for China their economy is
crumbling they are not even releasing
the GDP figures the belt and Road
interface is is is finished more or less
it's no longer progressing and the great
Chinese bid for super power status has
been completely derailed they don't even
have the Russia as a basal state it did
not happen India ensured it doesn't
happen
so because of this because the Americans
have more or less tamed the dragon at
least for now that's why
the the closeness that we were
witnessing in India us no longer exists
now the try that the relations are very
strained the relations between India and
the US these are very strange relations
right now the Americans are doing lots
of things that are anti-india
primarily through Pakistan also in in a
variety of other ways as well why are
there various possible States now what
was the quad the quad whatever you say
about this was primarily aimed at
containing China
the quadrilateral Alliance India the U.S
Australia and Japan now it's essentially
an India USA block because Australia and
Japan are U.S visal states Australia is
essentially a U.S corporation it's owned
by the U.S more or less and Japan is
under permanent military occupation by
the U.S so it's essentially in India in
India and U.S block that the quad is now
since the Chinese to some extent have
been contained obviously the Chinese are
still a formidable uh Naval power they
have a very large Navy they are still
building more warships they're still
building submarines they're still
bolstering their Armed Forces but
because the economy is stagnant now they
will not be able to continue this at the
same pace so
and the Americans have more or less
destroyed the Chinese chip making
industry and they are doing everything
they can to hamper the Chinese and
that's why the Americans are right now
it looks like they're pretty confident
that the Chinese have been more or less
contained for now at least yes and
that's why the quad will no longer get
the same importance as it used obviously
it is it still has a relevance but still
they still need to contain the Chinese
and ensure the Chinese don't cross the
various Island chains in the South China
Sea the champasi and the in the Pacific
Ocean region and so on so for that the
quad is important the Americans are
arming the Australians in the next 20
years Australia will acquire U.S made
nuclear submarines and so on
so the quad will remain relevant but it
will no longer have the same urgency
that it had let's say two years ago or
three years ago but it's still going to
be relevant so India and the us from the
Chinese perspective are still on the
same side India does need the US to some
extent to counter balance China India
can counter balance China on its own
using its whatever means it has its
disposal but it does need the Goodwill
of the US to some extent to a large
extent actually so um the quad will
remain relevant now what about India
Japan as long as Shinzo Abe was a big
Force as long as Shinzo Abe was alive
whether it was active in politics or not
he was the biggest Force in Japanese
politics
all right no matter what he was doing he
was the major Japanese politician the
major leader in Japan no other leader
even if they were the prime minister or
whatever could
hope to achieve the status the stature
that shinsabi had now shinzobe is out of
the way
he is out of the way he is gone he has
been assassinated now we are seeing a
very different kind of uh relationship
between India and Japan obviously India
and Japan the prime ministers made they
are very good relations and we all still
have a lot of common interests and all
that the Japanese are investing in India
in a variety of ways the the bullet
train project and so on but the Japanese
are now investing in Pakistan as well
which is something they never did before
as long Asian zombie was alive so yes we
know that the Japanese
are entirely controlled by the Americans
Japan is under permanent U.S military
occupation the Japanese Constitution has
been created by the written by the
Americans and the Americans have the
finals say the last say in in all major
policy decisions of the Japanese
government right so Japan is controlled
it's puppeteered by The Americans
and considering this fact there could be
a downturn in India Japan in India Japan
ties we already see Japanese
investments in Pakistan the Japanese are
waving off certain certain loans not
waving off but deferring certain loans
to Pakistan and you're also witnessing
uh
South Korea Pakistan defense deal so we
are witnessing these changes now
so there's gonna be an impact on India
Japan ties and the impact will not be
may not be very good one hopes that the
relationship between the two Nations
remains as strong and as vibrant and as
positive as it as it has always been
India and Japan are like civilizational
Brothers twins whatever you want to call
it
India has had a huge influence on
Japanese culture over the past nearly
two thousand years yeah so
civilizationally culturally we are very
much alike India and Japan
but in the past 150 or so years there's
been this big big wins of change in
Japan starting with the Meiji
restoration the attempt by the Meiji
Emperor to remove all traces of Dharma
from Japan which
kind of led to the events of the world
war one and World War II then the
Japanese came under American occupation
and now we know where it is so there
could be certainly a significant impact
on India Japan ties going forward
okay Ahmad says what's your views on
Iranian Kamikaze drones that are
creating havoc in the Ukrainian Capital
Kiev should India acquire some vaiboff
says why is Russia using Iranian drones
instead of their own drones can Russia
help Iran in their nuclear program
can Russia help Iran in the nuclear
program Russia certainly can help Iran
in their nuclear program but does Russia
want a nuclear-armed Iran not very far
from the Russian borders let's let's
take a look at the map
it's been a while since we use the map
but let's do it
so what do I mean by not far from
Russia's borders let's take a look at
the map so we know where India is yes we
know it let's go north north of India
you have
Russia
go westwards you have the Caspian Sea so
to the west of India there is this
temporary Nation called Pakistan we'll
just disregard that and so India's
Western neighbor is Iran
now north of Iran you have the Caspian
Sea and to the north of the Caspian Sea
you have Russia Russia is here right
so Iran and if you look at Nations like
Uzbekistan Kazakhstan Turkmenistan
Azerbaijan Etc Russia considers these
nations to be part of its geopolitical
area of exclusive influence right an
extension of Russia essentially
so the Russians I'm not sure if they
want a nuclear-powered nuclear-armed
Iran a nuclear-armed Iran is going to
have a mind of its own it's not going to
listen to anybody else that's what
nuclear weapons do to you right once you
have the one ring you are a whole
different entity you're no longer the
same
so um
I'm sure the Russians can help Iran in
its nuclear program if they so wish if
they so desire but do they so desire I
don't think so I may be wrong I don't
know what's going on in Mr Putin's mind
in the in the minds of the Russian
um
uh strategic Affairs uh planners and all
that but I think it doesn't make sense
for a nation like Russia or any Nation
to create a new nuclear ambition not so
far from its own borders right so that's
one thing so that's part of that's that
question answered now about the Iranian
Kamikaze drones
so yes it does appear like the Russians
have acquired a whole bunch of Iranian
Shahid Shahid drones uh these are
Kamikaze drones these are lightening
Munitions they loiter for a for an
extended period of time in the air and
then for and then
the strike and they destroy themselves
but they carry this this explosive
charge this this munition with them and
that explodes in that essentially
obliterates whatever Target they strike
so that's what a Kamikaze drone is the
Iranians have been manufacturing this
this good quality Shahid I think or
whatever it is and the Russians seem to
have acquired them and they have been
using them on
on on during as part of their war
against uh their their special operation
in Ukraine including on the capital city
give right in retaliation to the
destruction or the attempt to destroy
the the Crimean Bridge
so these drones are very effective and
their efficacy has been demonstrated in
the
in the arthasach conflict right the
Azerbaijan versus Armenia conflict with
that happened a year or so ago
and the Iranians are not the only nation
that manufactures such drones the Turks
have their own drones their own
loitering Munitions and the Israelis
also have this harope the harope Drone
which also is extremely efficacious and
extremely effective it's been proven to
work really well really well in in in
Warfare in conflict and India may have
acquired some of the Israeli drones and
India may have acquired the ability to
license manufacture those Israeli drones
possibly yeah I hear certain small bird
telling these or something like that
yeah
so uh these so this is the this is the
new 21st century form of warfare that's
how it's done
drones are extremely
effective very efficient and very useful
in Warfare especially Lloyd heading
Munitions they're loiter around flying
in circles from almost aimlessly
apparently aimlessly for two three four
hours and then without warning this
strike
and they can fly quite High I mean
depending on the on the manufacturer
depending on the type of drone they
could fly at a very high altitude almost
invisible and then they will suddenly
strike it and you know obliterate the
target
so should in India acquire India should
certainly acquire the drones ideally
India should manufacture its own drones
homegrown technology as long as that is
not the case we should acquire such
drones from friendly from friendly
neighbor Nations
friendly Nations like Israel for
instance so like I said I it is quite
possible that India may already have
Israeli harab drones and India may
actually have acquired the ability to
license manufacture these Israeli drones
within India it's possible so yes one
has to keep up with the latest
developments in military technology in
war fighting technology new tactics new
strategies and one must not be left
behind and I am pretty confident that
India is not going to be left behind in
the things India is now slowly or rather
not so slowly becoming a major drone
manufacturing nation and these things
are going to be very useful when it
comes to war fighting in the future yeah
okay harita says I live in France I've
interacted with many people from many
walks of life and from different regions
of France there is absolutely no
anti-america antenato sentiment in
France they believe the French believe
that Putin is evil Russia is the cause
of all their troubles including the
energy crisis and America is their
savior so why is the Indian media
highlighting the micro minuscule protest
that happened on one weekend in one
place and making it look like there is
widespread discontent why did the K
claim that France is close to quitting
NATO
um
so I have not been keeping up with the
news as it is shown on Indian media
because it is distasteful the Indian
media has no absolutely no understanding
of geopolitics and strategic Affairs
absolutely none whatsoever if you see
their analysis it is it is
ridiculous say ridicule yep so I don't
watch news so I'm not sure what the
Indian media has been saying in case
they have been highlighting some
protests well that's what the Indian
media does it has no idea of what's
really happening and they have no
ability to really interpret and analyze
what various events actually mean and
they often tend to blow small things out
of proportion and make it you know
fit a certain
narrative or perspective or whatever it
is so I don't know what the Indian media
has been doing but I kind of strongly
agree with you that most people in
France are pro NATO and very strongly
anti-russia
and as we know uh Russia and France have
had their historical dealings which have
not been always very positive whether
you look at the Napoleon Napoleonic era
or even before that or even after that
and so on Europe is has a very as a very
uh long and
rather fraught history of enmity between
the various Nations and uh so I I
totally understand that the people of
why the people of France would not have
a very very strongly or not have a very
good
sentiment towards Russia and obviously
the Americans did liberate them
to a large extent from the Nazis during
World War II so that is also there the
the Normandy the invasion of Normandy
from from the beaches of Normandy you
know and from there the the campaign
moved eastwards liberation of Paris
liberation of France eviction of the
Nazis all that
so yes the people of France most likely
like you're saying would have a very
pro-america and pro NATO sentiment no
anti-america anti-nato sentiment overall
there will be some pockets of resistance
maybe among the farmers or among certain
people who would feel that France would
be better off being outside NATO there
is there is obviously a political party
under Marine Le Pen and she is of the
opinion that France should leave NATO
but she obviously is not right now able
to win the presidency right
so um overall France is definitely going
to be pronato and anti-russia or most of
the Western European nations are going
to be like that so uh yeah so that is
indeed the case there will not be a very
strong or any or extensive anti-nato
anti-america or Pro Russia sentiment
within France whatsoever
the Western European the people of
Western Europe
consider Russia to be an Eastern Eastern
nation they do not consider Russia to be
a European nation a European culture
they consider the Russians to be an
Eastern people an Eastern culture so
it's a cultural thing it's an ethnic
thing and also it's a political thing a
geopolitical thing so yeah overall I
totally agree with harita's assessment
and her
reporting that the people of France are
definitely anti-russia and pro-us pro
NATO and I don't know what the Indian
media does I do not take the Indian
media seriously at all they have no
understanding of geopolitics they have
no understanding of what's happening in
the world their reporting is is
cringe-worthy very often for the longest
time when it came to foreign policy and
external Affairs the only the only
nation they thought of from the foreign
policy perspective was Pakistan
International Affairs means Pakistan
that's how it was until I think 90 until
2019 2020 until the gal one Clash and
then China came on the horizon slowly
nowadays everybody is a geopolitical
expert but they have no idea of what's
really happening so I have seen the
Indian media in action it's it's
terrible so let's not take it very
seriously shall we here
okay nitish says uh what's the question
wouldn't it be better for India to be in
line with America's interests and
develop the nation as Japan Germany and
other nations did after World War II
right so
interesting perspective interesting
question
so
it would have been good for India if
India had let's say aligned itself to a
certain extent for sure with the US the
U.S was willing to to make India one of
the five permanent members of the U.N
security Council even the Russians
wanted that and there were at least
three offers that were made to India and
the Great Indian magnificent prime
minister the great magnanimous Shri
nehruji refused those offers and
insisted that that position be given to
China instead that's a whole different
story right so the Americans did want
India on their side the the President of
the U.S Mr Kennedy he actually offered
India nuclear weapons technology
before the 1962 war with China had India
acquired the technology the Chinese
would not have dared fight a war against
India and try to invade India which they
succeeded in doing to some extent
so it would have been good for India's
interest but the question is how far
would it should we have would we have
gone with that
should India have become like you say a
nation like Japan or Germany well Japan
and Germany are under permanent U.S
military occupation that would be a
horrible thing for India because then
India would become
earlier we had the east in the company
now we would have the Americans and then
India's foreign policy and India's
internal policy would become an
extension of America's national interest
which would not be good for the people
of India and the nation and the
civilization of India
so it made sense it would have made
sense for India to align itself or Ally
itself with the US to a certain extent
without compromising on its core
interests on its national interests its
cultural interests and all those things
yeah
so it would have been good if it had
been done judiciously
in the right way
for that you need good leadership which
we did not have of course we had great
magnificent leadership but we do not
have good leadership
so uh that's what happened now we have
to understand
a different perspective as well
the people of Japan
Japan is an extremely prosperous Nation
it's the most
technologically advanced nation in the
whole world today isn't it the the most
technological Advanced nation in the
world Germany is Europe's
um
Industrial
Powerhouse it is Europe's biggest
economy largest economy uh the GDP per
capita of Japan is incredibly High
compared to that of India and the same
goes for Germany Japan's GDP per capita
May perhaps possibly be higher than that
of Germany as well so the people of
Germany in the people of Japan
experience great levels of personal
Prosperity very high standards of living
and yet these two nations are enslaved
these are not free Nations these are
nations that are laboring under
permanent foreign occupation
think about it like this
let's say you have a family of lions in
a zoo
lions lions
these Lions have kids of their own one
generation second generation those kids
have kids of their own and so on so
these new generations of lions live in
this big vast zoo with a lot of ground
territory which they can cover and there
is a fence around that so they have
excellent standards of living they get
fed regularly as much as they want to
eat they get great shelter they get
great they get water they get everything
they could imagine they could ask for
they live lives of great safety great
great luxury and no problems at all
right and yet they are slaves they're
enslaved they cannot go beyond the
confines of the zoo
so yes it's possible to enjoy great
living standards and great personal
individual prosperity in a nation that
is completely enslaved do you really
want that
that's the question you'd ask yourselves
it is and and the person who lives in
such a nation will have all the possible
will all will have all kinds of options
at the disposal develop great personal
freedom they'll be able to travel
wherever they want in the world at a
moment's notice they'll be able to
choose any career they want they'll be
able to give their children whatever the
children want so individually each
person will be
very prosperous and very free but
collectively the nation is still
enslaved understand the difference
between these two things
so yes had India become another slave
basal nation of the U.S maybe the
people's Prosperity would have been
great but India's culture would have
been destroyed in India's Freedom would
have evaporated
look at what's happening in Japan look
at the cultural erosion Japanese
sufferings look at the cultural erosion
and destruction of the culture of South
Korea
yeah sure they are prosperous they have
great standards of living very high
amounts of prosperity and yet where's
South Korea's culture and they have no
freedom
the nation doesn't have an independent
foreign policy the nation doesn't have
an independent military policy South
Korea's head of the military is a U.S
general is an American General
when it comes to Japan all major policy
decisions in Japan by the government
they
can be done only after the approval of
the Americans this is not a free Nation
so the question is do you want to be
prosperous but slaves or do you want to
struggle upwards and be free that's the
question
from a long-term perspective struggle is
better immediate Freedom immediate
Prosperity isn't great
because in the long term your nation
ceases to exist your culture ceases to
exist you become irrelevant and you
become subsumed by the superpower so
that's the thing we have to take a
long-term perspective a hundred year 200
year thousand year perspective for us in
India thousand years are not a big deal
we are the oldest surviving civilization
the oldest civilization that exists on
the planet more than 10 000 years old
for us a thousand years is not a big
deal
so we have a big 100 year or maybe a
thousand year perspective
and had we aligned ourselves with the us
the way the Japanese and the Germans
have been aligned as wasall States as
slaves it would have been the end of
Indian civilization even today as a free
Nation with an independent foreign
policy we are still facing so many
challenges from the cultural and
civilizational perspective there are so
many internal problems that are being
created within the nation by outside
forces
and one of the main trusts of this
outside forces is to approve and Destroy
Indian culture and civilization we are
seeing it everywhere
so imagine had India been a Visa state
of the Americans like the Germans have
been or the Japanese have been well the
German culture is more or less the same
as the American culture from a religious
perspective the same religion the
Germans are fine but the Japanese and
the Koreans see what's happened to their
culture
and their civilization it's it's
disappearing it's evaporating
so I would say that it would have been
good had India aligned itself
judiciously with America from the
perspective of India's own National
interest
in a way that benefited India and the
U.S simultaneously without one nation
you know getting more out of out of the
deal so that would have been good but
had India become like Germany or Japan
it would have been the end of India
so yeah that's that's the answer
okay boomi says what are your thoughts
on the new Air Base in gujarat's disa
which after its completion will reduce
the longer pending
strategic Gap gap of 355 kilometers
between the bhuj and utterly air bases
and how much will it be a game changer
in strengthening India's defense in
National Security
okay let's take a look at the air base
in Visa
so where is this up it's somewhere in
the north of India in the north of
Gujarat a bigger pardon so the old
capital of Gujarat was patan this town
here it was once the greatest City in
Gujarat north of tartan
uh you have this place called disha so
that's it's so it's in the vicinity of
this town called Visa that the new Air
Base will come up it's in Northern
Gujarat close to the Gujarat Rajasthan
border south of Mount Abu more or less
so we have an air base near budge in
Western Gujarat in Kutch right this is
budge over here if you can see this here
is budge and then there is uh this
utterly Air Base which I believe is in
the barmer region
of Rajasthan right somewhere here
so there is a big gap in between so this
new Air Base in Visa will fill that Gap
will it be a game changer not exactly a
game changer but it's gonna plug a gap
that is currently existing so it's a
good thing so I'm glad to see that these
steps are being taken to uh to
strengthen India's
defenses in India's national security
um
overall when it comes to Pakistan
Pakistan is is not that big of a threat
to India as as compared to China
but it certainly makes sense to uh plug
in any Gap to fill in any Gap that
currently exists vis-a-vis our error
defenses and an overall uh border
defenses Visa with Pakistan versus
Pakistan so it's a it's a very good step
that we are taking now that our economy
is growing our we can invest more in
these these things so it's going to be
in the long run a very good thing for
India as long as Pakistan temporarily
exists
then we will look at other things
okay Daniel Nicholson says
I'd love to know if India's latest
airport where the first flight was
completed by Indigo Airlines this month
uh so the latest airport near itanagar
in arunachal Pradesh is a message to
China which claims arunachal Pradesh do
not mess with modi's new India
considering the People's Republic of
China always raises objections to any
official visit to arunachal by Indian
dignitaries is India finally shedding
its laid-back approach to the
yesteryears of the yesteryears and being
more assertive now which is good
okay let's take a look at the where
itanagar is so ethanagar is in arunachal
Pradesh in the Far East of India
so this here region is called
arunachabadesh let me
um bring in
I don't know the terrain map here we are
one second
okay let's turn off the ring so yeah
that's easier now to see so arunachal
Pradesh is in the Far East of India and
the capital of arunachal Pradesh is
itanagar which is over here
all right so that's where itanagar is in
the context of the Indian geography
and
and we are now constructing a new
airport it's almost done I think the
first flight has already landed a test
flight by Indigo Airlines and I think
this new airport is going to become
operational in October 2022 which is
this month itself
and then we will have regular flights to
this place to itanagar from various
parts of the country so it's a very good
thing so what does it mean so any
airport any Landing Strip has dual use
it can be used for commercial aircraft
civilian aircraft it can also be used
for fighter jets for military aircraft
whether you go to um places like silchar
in Assam whether you go to places like
Lei in ladakh most of these airports in
the Border regions have dual uses most
of these are military airports that are
also used for civilian purposes and you
will see various military aircraft
parked over there or taking off on
Landing you see that all the time
so this is a very good step and and the
other thing I've noticed is that there
is a very very strong flurry of activity
by the border roads organization in all
our border regions the Border roads
organization the bro
is working tirelessly day and night to
construct the infrastructure the road
the road infrastructure in our border
regions whether it is highways whether
it is reinforcing the roads that already
exist whether it is laying better tarmac
better better tar roads or whatever they
are working day and night and they are
working in the most in-house hospitable
Terrain in the mountains in the Hills
they are creating roads on mountainsides
and all that so we are seeing that a
very strong push to create this
infrastructure in our border regions
which has been neglected for decades
ever since Independence right since 1947
India more or less neglected all the
border states they don't create any
infrastructure there whereas the Chinese
have created very good infrastructure
Road in in rail transport infrastructure
in the Border regions so India is now
playing catch-up it's doing it very very
strongly and we are creating we are
constructing roads we are constructing
Bridges we may be constructing Railways
in some places possibly and we are
obviously also constructing new airports
and Landing strips so all of this is as
part of the uh very strong concerted
effort to catch up with whatever
the Chinese have done and it's it's uh
it's a very good thing so what does it
mean it means that we it's not a message
to China it's about strengthening our
natural security it's about
strengthening and and
bolstering our border infrastructure
which obviously must be used by the
Armed Forces whenever the time comes for
that yeah
and yeah it's also a message to China in
in a way to not mess with India
so yeah India is indeed finally shedding
its so-called its laid-back approach of
yesteryears and it is definitely
becoming very much more assertive about
its National interest now which is a
very good thing
arsh says what is your take on the
Indian Air Force's new branch which will
mainly focus on developing and working
on Modern Technologies like drones land
to land missiles
land various things uh do you think they
learned this from Russia Ukraine war you
were also saying that we should focus on
this
um okay so let's see what the news says
about this one second
um yeah let's put
this article on the screen so that we
understand what's happening
so this is a news article from this
month itself about
a couple of weeks before today
so India get the iaf the Indian Air
Force gets a new Branch for Weapons
Systems
and it's going to uh it's going to span
four specialized streams surface to
surface missiles surface-to-air missiles
remotely piloted aircraft and weapon
system operators in Twin and multi-crew
aircraft
it's a very good thing
so essentially what we are doing is
we're going to save a lot of money and
we're gonna save a lot of effort so what
does this mean it's gonna save a lot of
money the new Branch will result in a
saving of more than 3400 crore rupees
due to reduced expenditure on flying
training
it will unify all weapon system
operators and of the iaf under a single
entity for operational development of
all ground base Etc weapons and so on
and so forth so it's a very good thing
we are finally going to do it in a
centralized manner there is going to be
no
duplication of effort no redundancy this
is going to be a single uh Branch think
about it like this right now if you have
a twin sitter fighter plane in which you
have two pilots
right now both of these people in in the
Twin City plane have to be trained
pilots
and they also have to be trained on how
to operate various weapon systems so the
guy sitting in the front is going to be
flying the plane the guy sitting in the
back back is gonna be Manning the weapon
systems but both have to be trained
pilots now with the creation of this new
Branch the guy sitting in the back the
guy who is Manning the weapon systems
does not need to be a trained pilot so
you are cutting down on the unnecessary
training that person can be a specialist
only in weapon systems he doesn't have
to know how to fly the plane the guy
sitting in the front will be fine find
the plane the guys thing is sitting in
the back will be specializing in how to
use the various missiles and whatever
else we are deploying on the aircraft
and the guy sitting in the front does
not have to worry about using the
weapons he only has to focus on the
flying of the of the aircraft similarly
there are certain such roles in combat
helicopters as well and so on so forth
so this new branch is going to train and
specialize in only the weapon systems
which is going to be a very essentially
a game changer for the Indian Air Force
so it is a very good development finally
we are reconfig configuring the Armed
Forces we are modernizing the Armed
Forces it's a very good development
obviously the armed forces have to keep
changing keep evolving with The Changing
Times yeah we have to focus on
efficiency on on cutting down on of
unnecessary expenditure cutting down on
unnecessary redundancy and all that so
this is now being taken up very strongly
with a great amount of seriousness it's
a very good step it's it's a very good
initiative the government has done and
the armed forces are undertaking is very
good uh have we learned this from the
Russia Ukraine war I don't think it's
only about the Russia current War it's
about how
the the global Military landscape is
changing with the Advent of new
technologies with the Advent of more
threats different kinds of threats we
have to keep evolving we have to stay
agile from the Armed Forces perspective
and that's what we're doing I obviously
have said that we have we should focus
on this we should focus on streamlining
and reforming the Armed Forces making
the Armed Forces a more lethal fighting
force in a variety of ways so yes this
is a very good step in the direction I'm
really happy to see that and this is one
step we need to take many more steps in
this direction but I am really glad to
see that this is happening so yeah
overall a very good step
says
in a recent interview Joseph Boral
representative of the EU for foreign
affairs said that since the second world
war Europe has built the best
combination of political Freedom
economic progress in Social cohesion
these three pillars have made Europe
great to live in organized Society
he also said that most countries lack
one or two of them
what's your take on this and what's
India's position on these three fronts
how can it be improved so this
individual Joseph Burrell is a Spanish
politician or something like that he
like you said is a
it represents the EU from the
perspective of Foreign Affairs or
whatever it is he's in some high ringing
position and recently he gave this gave
the speech in which he said that Europe
is like a garden
and other nations are like a jungle
right and he said that Europe uh has
built the most perfect and most
organized society that ever has existed
Europe um let's see what what the media
reports says I'm sure there is something
we can pull up
one second give me a second let me pull
that up
okay Joseph Burrell what do we have to
see about him
all right where is Mr Burrell
here we are Joseph Burrell apologizes
for controversial Garden versus jungle
metaphor but defends what he said
so uh
he says that the he did not mean to be
racist or it had no racist or cultural
or geographical connotation
include and so on that's what he said so
he said that Europe is a garden we have
built a garden everything works it's the
best combination of political Freedom
economic prosperity and social cohesion
that the humankind has been able to
build the three things together the rest
of the world he said is not exactly a
garden most of the rest of the world is
a jungle and the jungle could invade the
garden
he then referred to the EU ambassadors
as gardeners and
urged them to go to the Jungle
and and maybe you know reform the jungle
or civilize the jungle or whatever and
so on
so that's that's what this individual
has said
so what is my take on this
they have to understand something about
Europe
how did let's say Europe is a is a
garden right now how did it become a
garden
500 years ago Europe was the worst of
jungles
how did Europe become so prosperous
how did it make so much economic
progress you cannot have political what
what they call political freedom and
social cohesion with without economic
progress and a great amount of
prosperity how did they achieve what
they call economic progress they the
Europeans achieved economic progress by
destroying the rest of the world
there there were Gardens outside of
Europe in the past they destroyed those
Gardens and turned those Gardens into
wastelands and jungles and they
plundered everything of value out of
those Gardens including Africa including
China and mainly India and enriched
themselves at our expense that's how
they were able to create their own
garden by destroying the rest of the
world Europe produces nothing Europe is
small compared to the rest of the world
how did the entire wealth of the world
end up in Europe
through piracy through plunder through
destruction through looting
through genocide and now they say that
we are the best in the world we have
created the best combination blah blah
blah
the problem now
the problem now is
that the rest of the world is rising
again and the Europeans produce nothing
of any integrate value
and without producing anything of any
great value in the future their
economies are going to go down and the
rest of the world is going to rise India
is going to rise China is going to rise
and once the European colonization of
Africa ends it still hasn't ended once
it ends hopefully in the future Africa
will also Rise Again Africa has
incredible amounts of Natural Resources
the African nations should be the most
prosperous nation in the world but
what's happening is that all the wealth
is still being funneled out of Africa
into the West that's what's happening
so when all these things end which will
happen with the rise of the East
Europe Europe will go back to its
natural
status of being the one of the first
jungles of the world
so uh that's my take on this what's
India's position on this India's
position we we are doing economic
progress right now we are a long way
away from regaining our historical
position of being the great largest
economy in the world but it will happen
social cohesion it we don't quite have a
great deal of social coercion right now
there are lots of internal problems
which have all been created by Outsiders
India and these are efforts that are
still happening right now actively to
create more divisions within India and
these are all being financed and
fermented by external forces and Powers
we know who they are and we know how
they're doing it they're trying to
create divisions on ethnic and social
and cultural and religious Lines within
India
and this isn't this is something that's
a project that is actively being
conducted by them so yes there are
problems when it comes to social
cohesion economic progress is happening
it's it's going to take some time maybe
a decade or two for India to rise to uh
to the possession of one of the largest
economic economies in the world India
soon enough will be the number two or
number three economy in the world it's
it's just a matter of time as long as
there is no big Calamity like a great
War or conflict
uh so from the economic progress
perspective India is doing well India is
on the right track social cohesion there
are forces outside of India that are
trying to undermine social cohesion in
India right now we know who they are and
we know what they're doing and how
they're doing it when it comes to
political Freedom India India has
political Freedom the people of India
have genuine political Freedom India is
one of the few genuine democracies in
the world India is a vibrant though
chaotic multi-party democracy
look at the U.S it's a two-party state
that's not a democracy that's a farce
it's just one step ahead of North Korea
and China which are both one-party
States
North Korea has a single political party
and when their leader stands for
election everybody has to vote for him
the same goes for China in China the
people can't even vote there's a whole
different weird system there so China is
a one-party state
North Korea is a one-party State the US
is just one step ahead of that the US is
a two-party State yeah there are two or
three insignificant political parties
that don't really count these are
insignificant political parties if you
want to make any difference as a
politician in the U.S you have to either
be a democrat or a republican that's it
there are some parties those are
insignificant parties so please don't
quote that I don't need that no one
needs that it's those are irrelevant and
insignificant political parties the only
two parties that really matter and
really count uh the Republican Party in
the Democratic party so-called
Democratic party so it's a two-party
system we how how can you call that a
democracy who's going to represent the
hopes and aspirations of the various
minorities in the U.S in India every
single minority every single region of
India has political parties multiple
political parties that uh that represent
that those regions and those minorities
why are there no why is there no
political party in the U.S that stands
up for the rights and hopes and
aspirations of the Native Americans why
is there no political party in the US
that stands up for the hopes and
aspirations and rights of the
African-Americans or the Latinos
or or or the Hindus or the Jews or
whatever why is there no such system why
does everything have to be Force fitted
into either the Democrats or the
Republicans
so this is not a genuine democracy it's
a farce so India is far ahead in terms
of political freedom
compared to Nations like the us or
Australia which is a joke
Australia is entirely owned by the U.S
or or nations like the UK which don't
even have a political which don't even
have a constitution the UK doesn't have
a constitution the UK is a
constitutional monarchy it's ruled by by
a king
and you may say the king is a figurehead
a puppet only a name not so true not so
true
you think it's that way it's made to
appear to you like the the king of
England
um doesn't really matter it's only a
figure he's only a figurehead he's not
quite only a figurehead
but yeah if you want to know more about
that you need to do your own research
I'm not telling you about it right now
I'm not getting into that so I think
India is on the right track India is
doing well from the economic progress
perspective India is doing very well for
the political Freedom perspective better
than the West
from the social Cohen perspective the
West is trying to destabilize social
cohesion in India but we will overcome
this these attempts and we will come out
on top
all right
priyal says
can you please shed some light on the
recent Hunger index reports which had
placed India on one of the lowest spots
despite
other countries undergoing economic
natural and hunger crisis
Sanju says why do what do you think it
looks when India ranks so low
lower than both the neighboring
countries one was devastated with floods
on the hunger index report when India
sent food relief during covet pandemic
and Ukraine crisis to so many countries
in need how can India rank so low is it
a waste conspiracy to show India in a
negative light
or is there
or is there something that we as a
nation are not giving enough Focus I
have got a lot of questions about the
hunger index thing some people are
saying that India is not doing well they
actually believe this nonsense
India has sent food Aid to so many
nations during the covet crisis during
during other crisis as well India is a
next India is a net exporter more or
less of food especially when other
nations require aid from India
nobody in India is suffering from Hunger
the U.N reports have shown that India
has more or less eradicated extreme
poverty
India has brought more people out of
excellent poverty than any other nation
in the world in the pastored roughly a
decade right so what is this entire
thing this hunger index report first of
all this is not a scientific report it
was done in a very arbitrary basis the
sample size was about 3000 people if I'm
not mistaken and they asked very very
vague questions
in order to suit their agenda
so we don't have to take these things
seriously I don't understand why Indians
take these things seriously and they
actually start believing these things
who are foreigners should to decide
where India ranks on whatever index yeah
so what is the purpose of this hunger
index thing is it a conspiracy to show
India in a negative light or is it
something else
the purpose of this hunger index thing
of putting India very low on the hunger
index
the purpose of doing this why are they
doing this they're doing it so that they
can mislead the voters of India and make
the people of India think that the
government is doing very poorly
and hopefully
this will affect a Raheem change in
India in 2024. that is the real reason
they're doing this they want to
undermine
India they want to make people in India
feel that the government is not doing
well because Indians still crave Western
approval in a western stem of approval
and Western certificates so they will
give you bad certificates they will say
you know you're not doing well they also
the India the nation is doing very
poorly and most people in India they
believe this nonsense so the objective
is
to hopefully from their perspective or
through the current government in 2024
and bring a weak government to power or
maybe a government led by one of their
favorite puppet individuals like I have
said in the past there are lots of
aspiring zelenskies in India I am not
pointing fingers at any individual I am
not taking anybody's name I'm not even
going there
but you know what I mean there are
plenty
there is no shortage of aspiring
zelenskies in India zelinski is a NATO
puppet he's a western puppet
he's not serving the people of Ukraine
he's not serving the nation of Ukraine
he's serving his Western Masters
and it's resulting in the complete
destruction of Ukraine as a result there
are plenty of aspiring zelinskis in
India and the West would like one of
these zelenskies to come to power in
2024 and how do you do that
you do that by making people doubt the
performance of The Go of the government
by issuing these false uh
indices in reports and saying that India
is doing very poorly in the Hunger index
Indians are starving to death what
absolute nonsense so please don't
believe this nonsense these are all lies
and fabrications designed to mislead you
the people of India do not fall prey to
these manipulations and distortions and
lies please don't that's all I say
okay
Vishnu says what is the geopolitical
stand of Brazil because it is a member
of brics the Chinese block
okay and it's counted as a strategic
Ally of the U.S but the U.S doesn't
support its ask for permanent seat in
the U.N security Council at least
through words
why is Brazil the sixth largest country
and perhaps the biggest economy in Latin
America why is it unable to influence
World politics in economics
so you can't influence World politics
and economics without having an
independent foreign policy and without
being a major power it may be the sixth
largest nation in the world but it from
the economy perspective it's it's not a
big economy if you're not a big economy
and you are substitute the subsidiary to
other bigger Powers then you are
insignificant and irrelevant so Brazil
does seek something okay let's
understand the history
have you heard of the Monroe Doctrine
the Monroe Doctrine was the U.S foreign
policy in the 19th century more or less
since the 19 since the 1820s onwards
so you had the Napoleonic Wars so
understand this the Americans broke free
of the UK of England
in the American Revolution they became
an independent nation
uh then you had a lot of French
involvement in North America
uh the Americans brought the Louisiana
thing from Napoleon for a very cheap
price then they later bought Alaska from
the Russians then they were able to
evict the French more or less from North
America
in a variety of ways then there was a
great deal of Spanish colonization in
South America
I hope you all know where South America
and North America is if you don't let's
go to the map because that's what we do
so let's take a look at the map we're
talking about Brazil and North America
and the Western Hemisphere
so the Western hemisphere is right here
North America and South America Brazil
is the largest nation in South America
so the in the night in the 1900 in the
19th century the Americans said the
Monroe Doctrine which opposed any
European involvement in
the geopolitics of the western
hemisphere in any way whatsoever the
Americans said that we will oppose any
European
effort
to influence outcomes or to colonize in
a nation in the Western Hemisphere
when this Doctrine was put forth in the
1820s at that time the Napoleonic Wars
had ended in most of the nations of
South America had more or less broken
free of Spanish colonization so the
Americans said that we will not allow we
will oppose any further attempts by
European nations to try and colonize
Any Nation in the western hemisphere in
the Americas which essentially said that
we are going to be the dominant power
the dominant force in the Americas and
we will enforce this dominance
militarily and the Monroe Doctrine did
not put any limitations on to what
extent The Americans
could you know influence things in the
Americas
um so that's what that's what the Monroe
Doctrine was eventually you had all
these weak Nations that that emerged out
of the Americas the Americans fought
several Wars there was the U.S Spanish
War as well which uh led to the freedom
of Cuba and various other conflicts
Hawaii was annexed by the Americans as a
consequence of the Monroe Doctrine then
you had the first world war the second
world war the Germans opposed that the
British also opposed that but eventually
the Americans came out on top and all
the nations in the Americas essentially
were subsidiaries to the American uh
National interest in American foreign
policy
as a consequence of this you had various
weak nations in the in the Americas
including Brazil
now now Brazil is is a large Nation from
the geographical area perspective it's
not a major economy it's not a very
strong economy
uh it does obviously seek some
Independence it does every nation seeks
Independence Every Nation seeks to no
longer be somebody else's State and
that's why Brazil is part of the brics
block I would not yeah brics is still
more or less dominated by China but
Russia and India together can very much
counterbalance China
in brics and now more nations want to
become part of brics I believe Argentina
also wants to be part of brics uh Iran
has applied to be part of brics one
hears that Saudi Arabia also wants to
become part of brics so we are
witnessing a global realignment of of
the of the of the entire Global World
Order
uh so the question is why is Brazil
unable to influence World politics
because it is not a strong Nation it
doesn't have a strong economy it's not a
major economy I don't think Brazil is in
the top 10 of the economies unless I'm
mistaken it's not a major economy it's
not a major military power as well there
is no major military power in the
Americas ex apart from the United States
No Other Nation is a major military
power and so on so because of these
these factors Brazil is currently not
able to
have any kind of genuine major influence
on world politics World geopolitics or
World economics for that you have to
become first of all a large economy a
major economy and then you also have to
build up your own military strength
based on the kind of economy you have
and you also need to have an independent
foreign policy right now every single
nation in the Americas whether it's
Canada whether it's Mexico whether it's
Chile or it's Argentina whether it's
Brazil or whoever else all of these
nations are to some extent in one way or
the other
vasaltates of the US and they don't
really have very independent foreign
policies and that's why none of them
really matter from a geopolitical or
economic perspective on the global Arena
right
somebody Jenna says in the Falklands War
in the Falklands Island War Argentina
was the aggressor yes sir
asserts that Argentina was the aggressor
in the Falklands Island War
I I think I've said this multiple times
in public perception
the person
who strikes first is always seen as an
aggressor
the the person or the party that is the
first to take kinetic action is always
seen as the aggressor
now let's let's take a look at the
geography of the of the of the malvinas
right all right right we are at the
right place
so the so-called so let's see where
where the UK is you see what the UK is
it's over here right can you see United
Kingdom over here on the map yeah this
is the UK now let's see where the
malvinas islands are or the so or the
Falkland the so-called Falkland Islands
are
go several thousand kilometers
southwards cross the Equator keep going
thousands of kilometers South and all
the way here near Antarctica off the
coast of Argentina you have the malvinas
islands
let's let's try and calculate the
distance in a straight line from the
malvinas to the UK roughly measure
distance from here
all the way
to let's say London
it's 12 almost 13 000 kilometers how
does a territory how does a bunch of
islands the 13 000 kilometers away from
England how does it become part of
England on by what right does Britain
claim that it's part of their territory
it's right next to Argentina so it's see
we understand that Argentina the
population of Argentina are immigrants
all the nations of South America are
nation states were created by by
colonization and so on that's fine
but let's look at it from a geographical
perspective it's very clear that this
bunch of islands this archipelago should
be part of Argentina it's nowhere near
the UK it's 13 000 kilometers away from
the UK it's right off the coast of
Argentina so by All rights it should
belong to Argentina and yet it is under
illegal and temporary British occupation
so the argentinians decided to take
matters into their own hands and they
decided to uh Liberate the islands
through military action so they were the
first to fire shots and that's why this
gentleman somebody is saying that they
were the aggressors when somebody's
occupying your territory illegally for
for a very long time and then you take
military action are you gonna be should
you be called the aggressor no the
person who is occupying territory
illegally is the aggressor and you are
simply taking steps to to seek Justice
and to redress the Injustice that has
been carried out so in that case you are
not the aggressor but see that's how
gullible ends and that's how gullible
people are that's how simple-minded
people are that whoever fights fires the
first shot is going to be seen as
aggressor whether they're right or wrong
doesn't matter
that's the problem so it's very clear
that the the malvinas islands should by
All rights belong to Argentina not to
the UK I would say that the UK is and is
is currently temporarily and illegally
occupying the malvinas islands they need
to be evicted out of there and this is
happening obviously because of the
support of larger nations of more
powerful relations I think we can all
guess which that powerful nation is
anyhow
so I completely disagree with this very
very simplistic simple-minded statement
with Argentina was the aggressor
Argentina was seeking to redress the
Injustice that had been perpetrated upon
it by the colonial imperialistic British
occupation of the malvinas islands they
were simply trying to redress
that Injustice they failed and because
they fired the first shot simple-minded
people say that Argentina was aggressive
which is so wrong
tomorrow when the time is right India is
going to retake Pok and liberate Tibet
if India fires the first shot are you
going to say that India is aggressor how
stupid would that be think about it
right next
okay teaching says
what was the lifestyle of the people of
the Far East of India during the during
The Vedic times how did they live what
did they eat did they have kings and
queens what was the lifestyle like okay
let's understand where is the Far East
of India very good question
so when chaching refers to the Far East
of India she refers to what most people
still even now refer to as the so-called
Northeast of India the northeast of
India
is what I call the Far East of India
which should correctly be called the
finance of India which comprises the
various States over here
Manipur tripura these are the various uh
states that comprise this region right
this is the Far East of India so the
question is what was the lifestyle of
the people of this region like during
The Vedic times how did they live what
kind of Lifestyle did they have what
kind of food did they eat eat did they
have kings and queens and so on now when
we talk about The Vedic Age we are most
likely talking about a time
that that is about between six to eight
thousand years before today at least
maybe more than that because of the
dating of the river Saraswati which is
mentioned in the rigveda in the rig Veda
the Saraswati is mentioned is a very
strong massive powerful River Roaring
River mother of floods and the last time
the Saraswati was in her prime was about
6000 BC which is 8 000 years before
today which indicates that rig weather
was written closer to a 6000 BC then to
later on so the most likely The Vedic
Age was around six thousand four
thousand five thousand six thousand BC
maybe before that somewhere around that
time a very long time ago maybe eight
thousand years ago maybe even before
that or somewhere in that time period
so during this time what was the
lifestyle of the people of the Far East
like we don't know there are no records
that we have and nobody has done any
archaeological work in this region of
any significance for instance
how many archaeological sites do we know
of in nagaland president how many
archaeological sites do we know of in in
Manipur in meghalaya in mizoram
entrapura almost none at all I don't
know what the archaeologists and
historians are doing in this region
almost no work at all so we don't know
what archaeological sites exist there we
don't know what archaeological artifacts
we can find from this region and we
don't know what the lifestyle was was
like at the time what we do know is that
the region of which is now known as
Tibet
and and the so-called xinjiang
temporarily occupied vagina it was once
known as uttarakuru this was in a time
after The Vedic Age right after The
Vedic Age at that time there was no
Tibet there were no Tibetan people
living there this entire region was
inhabited by Indian origin kingdoms and
people
which is present day Central Asia
so around five thousand six thousand
years before today there were no Tibetan
people living in this region there were
Indian origin people living here even
during the more in Iraq where the hothan
kingdom was founded by Indians
from the mauryan uh era of India
and and so on so it looks like the
various other people who lived there
today the so-called ugors and the our
good friends the Tibetan people Etc they
came in later from further east from
further east uh
and we know that the most of the
languages that are spoken in the Far
East of India are classified classified
as tibeto-burman languages some of these
languages like the the languages in
Assam are classified as Thai languages
so it looks like at some point in time
people migrated into the Far East of
India from further east maybe from the
United region of of currently
temporarily in China or maybe from from
further north from the Mongolia region
or somewhere else we don't quite know we
will have to do lot of research to
understand the migration patterns and
how people migrate into this region and
and at what time they migrated into this
region we will need to do archaeogenetic
work population genetic research we will
have to do archaeological work in a lot
of such research which will together
help us form a good idea of when the
migrations happen and how long have the
people of let's say Assam the home
people will been living there how long
have the various uh Naga Clans been
living there the various uh how long
have the methane people been living in
in the Manipur region and so on and so
the Missouri the Miso people and so on
currently we have next to no idea at all
because our historians have not done
their job our archaeologists or not not
done the job so unfortunately I don't
have the answer nobody has the answer
you will have some stories who will make
certain claims but those claims will be
baseless because nobody has done the
research on which you can make such
claims you go to the university of
Manipur in imphal you go to the
university of nagaland in kohima or
whatever I would like to go to those
places and and talk to the professors of
History over there and ask them what
have you guys been doing unfortunately
they've been doing nothing
so as of today as of 2022 nobody has the
answer of what was the lifestyle of
these people like
uh most likely the people who live in
the Far East of India today whether it's
in nagaland Manipur Assam meghalaya or
whatever else most likely
some of their ancestors came from
further east or further north and some
of the resistance would have been part
of overall the the Western regions of
India obviously it's it's all a mixed
dog it's a it's it's uh you don't have a
single line of ancestry you have
thousands of lines of ancestry that's
how it is so uh the answers still elude
us because our historians and our
researchers have not done their job uh
so I don't know as of today no one knows
what kind of Lifestyle they had what
they ate did they have kings and queens
of course they had kings and queens uh
historically
most of us
us as in Homo sapiens most most humans
have always had the uh monarchical
system kings and queens democracy is a
fleeting experiment we had an indigenous
form of democracy in India for the
longest time the janapada system uh that
no longer exists today we are laboring
under this false Western democratic
system
but historically human beings have
always lived under kings and queens but
some of them have been good some of them
may have been bad but it's always been
the monarchical system so yes the
ancestors of the people of the forest of
India would definitely have had kings
and queens and most likely they would
have come from most of them would have
come from further east at some various
points in time and many of their
ancestors would also have come from the
west of the region which which is
colloquially called as Mainland India
which is not exactly a correct term
anyhow that's what one can say about
this
saurabh says how many evidences of
burial of selected bones after cremation
were found in the in this Valley
Civilization what about Cemetery burials
there
uh the where they first generation
immigrants or original inhabitants
that's a good question uh let me put
something on the screen
okay
uh this is something I had tweeted a
long long time ago not a very long time
ago I think 2019 or something
so there is this uh paper that has been
published in which and I have summarized
it over there there is evidence that the
harappans practiced cremation there is
strong evidence that symmetry burial was
limited almost exclusively to first
generation immigrants hence burials may
not represent the Harappan population at
all
and let me show you the actual paper
itself what it says
where is it here it is
evidence for patterns of selective
herbal Urban migration in the greatest
Indus greater Indus Valley region and so
on
so it says that
um
what does it say so essentially if you
read the paper it tells you that if the
paper
says that it is quite likely that
whatever burials you find in the
Saraswati Sindhu region may actually
represent first generation immigrants to
the region and it is quite it is quite
possible that the majority of the
population of the region practiced
cremations yeah we do find burials
but those burials may represent first
generation immigrants and not the actual
natives of the region that's very
possible because cremation has always
been the major practice in India in in
funeral rituals right and we do find
evidence of cremations in the Sarasota
region pots that are filled with ashes
and burned bones of individuals who have
been committed you find that you find a
few burials but not as many as you would
find if everybody practiced burials so
it looks like
the burials that you find could
represent first generation immigrants to
the region why would there be immigrants
to the region this was the most
prosperous region in the entire world
the most technologically advanced
civilization that ever existed and the
most prosperous region in the whole
world at the time today everybody wants
to go to the U.S because it is so
Advanced and so prosperous so in the old
days there was India that was in the
region so people from all over the world
wanted to come immigrate there and
settle down there and people from
elsewhere would have had different
customs
so after a generation two or two they
would assimilate culturally with the
local population and then they would
practice the same Customs but maybe the
first generation immigrants would
continue practicing burials
and that's what probably likely these uh
burials that we find represent so that's
a possibility so that's uh what that
paper tells us and that's I would say a
significant possibility
does height matter for guys well yes and
no I mean if you're tall you don't
complain about it it's good it always
feels good to be tall but many people
who have achieved a lot aren't that tall
and that doesn't really matter so what
really matters in the long run is what
you achieve in your life not what your
height is there are lots of tall people
who achieve nothing in life and there
are lots of short people who achieve a
great deal
Napoleon was not a very tall guy he was
a short man and I believe even Julius
Caesar is supposed to have not been a
very tall person there have been many
great people who have not been tall what
really matters in your life is how much
you contribute to society
if you are able to contribute more to
society than you take out of it then you
have then you have lived a meaningful
and meaningful and good and productive
life so height doesn't really matter
obviously
it it has a psychological effect and you
obviously don't complain if you're at
all but overall that doesn't really
matter what matters is what you do with
your life not how tall you are you can't
choose how tall you are what your skin
color is what family you're born in what
nation you're born in what you can
actually choose is what you do with your
life so that's what matters your height
doesn't overall really matter so don't
really get stuck about whether you're
tall or short it's not important
archana says 23 October is Diwali will
you not burst crackers I think Diwali is
tomorrow 24th October doesn't matter if
it's today if it's today I think the
whole week should be Diwali will I not
burst crackers I will burst a lot of
crackers it's part of our culture it's
part of a tradition
don't believe the woke idiots who tell
you that it causes pollution so crackers
don't cause pollution on Christmas day
how's that so how come crackers don't
cause any pollution on New Year's Day
how come crackers don't cause pollution
when there are celebrity weddings where
lots of crackers are burst why do they
only cause pollution on Diwali
what hypocrisy
so I am going to
burst a whole lot of crackers tomorrow
I'm gonna have a lot of fun and I invite
you all to join me in bursting crackers
and celebrating Diwali the way it is
supposed to be celebrated it's one day
one day don't give up your culture don't
give up your Traditions bus trackers go
for it
so that's what I would say Enjoy Diwali
and I wish you all a very Happy Valley
okay let's take a few questions from the
live chat I am I'm sure there are more
questions that I have missed but let's
take some questions from the live chat
for a couple of minutes
um
yeah
the maharaja's elephant says the UK
holds air drills over Scotland yeah well
Scotland is currently under temporary UK
occupation under temporary British
occupation and it will soon be liberated
I hope so yes
um Bobby says it's it's just the amount
Everything at Once lighting up can cause
smog I suppose not major see obviously
when you burst a cracker it's gonna give
off some smoke some some pollution it's
just one day uh when it comes to North
India it's these double burning that
causes the majority of the population
more than 99 of the population of the
pollution
and various Studies have demonstrated
this that that's that preventing people
from bursting crackers in Diwali has no
effect on the pollution
so there would be maybe a one percent
effect it's it's it's nothing major it's
just one day that people celebrate and
it's just wrong to to to
force people to give up a tradition
that's thousands of years old
and by the way gunpowder was invented in
India and we have various paintings that
go back centuries maybe even more than
thousand years that depict the fireworks
being used in Diwali celebrations in
India so I think it's just one day
obviously one needs to be mindful of
pollution one cannot do this on a
day-to-day daily basis on a routine
basis do it one day and then stop be
disciplined I I think Indians are very
disciplined from the perspective people
don't burst trackers every single day
it's one day and they should be allowed
to do it and if there are forces within
India of certain institutions certain
governments that are trying to prevent
Indians from celebrating the culture
that is not the right thing and these
governments should be elected out of
power
all right voted out of power I mean
gunpowder was invented in India that is
indeed correct then powder was invented
in India not in China
look it up look it up I am not giving
you any references right now because it
would take me time to dig it up but
again powder was invented in India look
it up do some of your own research learn
how to fact check what I am saying right
go ahead
manjunath says is marriage necessary
it's up to you your choice you want to
marry get married if you want to live a
life without marriage that's entirely
your choice who's gonna Force you I'm
not forcing you
it's it's a social custom it ensures
there is no conflict in society when you
have a couple who essentially stay
together for life that ensures stability
of the society
and no conflict because look at the way
the West is today good God there is
there is no stability in society
people get divorced after a year or two
there are childless I mean there are
there are single parent families
children who grow up without this
without the benefit of two parents and
see how Society is deteriorating see how
much Strife there is in society
how much crime there is in society and
so on so marriage overall is a good
thing it's part of all societies it's
always been part of all societies today
there is this campaign in the west to to
destroy the institution of the family
it's not a good thing so overall I say I
would say that marriage is an integral
part of any stable Society but from an
individual perspective it's entirely
your choice whether you want to get
married or not nobody should be should
force you to do one thing or the other
it's your choice you decide the way
you're gonna live your life
friends are not just our friends they
are our own people
they are our close relatives cousins
brothers sisters whatever you want to
call them
so thank you and I really appreciate it
and we we love you all you are our own
people and we should all celebrate our
things our our festivals together
and take the nation forward as it should
all right
okay let's take maybe one or two
questions
can India win a two-front war well what
India can do mostly
is ensure it doesn't lose a two-front
war
that India can certainly do
that is almost a guarantee
that's almost a guarantee that India
will certainly not lose a two-front war
because India has
videos
tools at its disposal that can be used
when certain red lines are crossed so
India certainly cannot be defeated in a
two-front war
in a few years India will actually be in
a position to win a two-front war give
it some time and work hard to make India
a 10 trillion dollar economy all of you
together once we do that
we're gonna win a two-front war if
required if it ever happens
all right
uh ask me a good question one good
question
um Roger says UK is paying eight hundred
thousand dollars to hide Mount buttons
Diaries why okay so I haven't heard of
what's happening is it is it true or not
that they are paying this much of money
to hide his Diaries but in case it's
true I would not be surprised Mr mount
button
her buttenberg
he was a man of certain unusual
proclivities that would be considered to
be criminal Tendencies today yeah look
it up read upon his criminal Tendencies
and maybe he recorded his various
activities in his diaries that would
kind of expose
his
um
unorthodox Tendencies and proclivities
so maybe that's why they're doing it you
know because he's somebody that's that's
a kind of kind of portrait is a great
member of of of the nation or whatever
right that's why
uh
what else do we have I think we are
almost at the end of today
um
do we have any other good question
let me try and find one good question
come on
one good question
um
how can I be smart like you I'm not
smart man I just read a lot I've just
read a lot I've always been curious I've
always read a lot since I was a kid and
that's why I have a whole lot of
what people in the past considered to be
completely useless knowledge but maybe
it's not so useless
see don't ask yourself how you can be
smart like person X or person wire
person Z ask yourself how how can you
reach the full the maximum of your
potential
so you do that by being open-minded by
being curious by by always being
receptive to knowledge most of us we
stop learning after as soon as we are
out of the education system that is a
very bad thing we should never ever stop
learning
so as long as you keep learning you're
gonna keep growing and you're gonna be
smart
so that's what I could say in brief all
right my friends we are at the end of
today's session thank you very much for
your viewership thank you very much for
all your questions for participating I
wish you once again a very Happy Diwali
enjoy yourselves tomorrow go burst
crackers to your heart's content
and I will see you in next week's live
stream until then take care